Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
I haven't learned "sadness" yet.
kanashimi wa mada oboerarezu
And I'm just starting to grasp "misery".
setsunasa wa ima tsukami hajimeta
Even this feeling I hold towards you.
anata e to idaku kono kanjou mo
Is now turning into "words".
ima kotoba ni wakatteku
Waking up from the dream of this unknown world.
michi naru sekai no yume kara mezamete
I spread these wings and fly.
kono hane wo hiroge tobi datsu
Once I fly,
habataitara
I won't be coming back, I said.
modorena ito itte
And I set out.
mezashita no wa
For that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Knowing I'll find the answer,
tsuki nuketara
If I pierce through it.
mitsukaru to shitte
if I break free,
furikiru hodo
From that blue, blue sky.
aoi aoi ano sora
Deprived of Eternal Sleep
(ナルト)んっ？
Get a move on, Naruto!
(サクラ)なに ボヤボヤしてるのよ ナルト！
(サクラ)もう置いてくわよ！
We'll leave you behind.
Is he trembling?
《サイ : 震えているのか？》
ぐっ！
《ハハハッ！
任務中でも やろうと思えば
できるってばよ！》
I can totally do this
even on a mission if I try.
《やっぱり 怖いんだ…》
I knew it. He's afraid...
(ヤマト)ん？
《あれだ！ 昨日の…》
It was that talk...
from yesterday.
What's keeping
Captain Yamato?
((しっかし ヤマト隊長 遅いなぁ。
Really. I wonder
where he went off to.
ホント どこまで行ったのかしら？
(３人)ん？
ああ！ ヤマト隊長…。
Captain Yamato?
Yikes!
うっ!?
ハハハハ！
Captain Yamato!
ヤマト隊長 ビックリさせんなってばよ。
Don't scare us like that!
すまん すまん！ つい…。
Sorry, sorry.
I couldn't help it...
ったく… ヤマト隊長の演出は
冗談抜きで➡
Your acting is always serious
and totally scary, Captain Yamato!
いつも怖すぎなんだってば！
ハハハハ！ からかいがいがあるな！
ナルトは ホント。
It's really worthwhile
teasing you, Naruto.
はぁ… でも隊長
さっきの話なんですけど➡
But Captain, about what
we were talking about earlier.
Why would someone
violate a grave?
なんのために
お墓を暴くんでしょうか…。
ひどい。
That's awful...
Yeah.
うん。 まぁ 普通は
金持ちの墓なんかを狙って➡
Well, usually the graves of
wealthy individuals are targeted
一緒に入れられた装飾品なんかを
奪っていくんだけどね。
and items such as ornaments buried
with the body are stolen...
But the body and treasure were
untouched in these grave robberies.
(ヤマト)でも この墓荒らしは
遺体も お宝も そのまんま。
The grave robberies have
been occurring frequently
その墓荒らしが
これから向かう火ノ寺を中心に➡
within a five-kilometer radius
around the Fire Temple
半径５キロメートルの範囲内で
頻繁に起こっている。
where we are now headed.
火ノ寺？
うん。
Fire Temple?
Right. It's the temple that
commissioned this mission.
(ヤマト)この任務を
依頼してきた寺だ。
墓荒らしの捕獲に
協力してほしいとの依頼だが➡
Their request is for us to help out with
the capture of the grave robbers.
But I get the feeling there's something
more to these grave robberies.
この墓荒らし
そう単純じゃないような気がする。
実は この寺の周辺には
４つの隠し墓がある。
As it happens,
there are four hidden tombs
in the area around this temple.
Any chance the grave robbers were
targeting those hidden tombs?
もしかして墓荒らしは
その隠し墓を狙った…？
Yeah, there's a
good chance of that.
うん。 その可能性が高い。
Just a minute.
What are hidden tombs?
ちょっと待ってよ！
隠し墓って何なの？
The variety of information
resting in the graves
(ヤマト)忍者の肉体には 死してなお
さまざまな情報が➡
along with the deceased Ninja
is like a gold mine.
それこそ
宝の山のごとく眠っている。
Like Sasori whom
you fought before...
キミが戦った あのサソリも…。
あっ… 三代目風影の
遺体を利用して傀儡に…。
He used the body
of the Third Kazekage
and turned him
into a puppet.
That's right.
(ヤマト)そう 上級の忍者で
あればあるほど➡
The greater the Jonin Ninja,
the higher the utility value there would be.
その利用価値は高い。
だから遺体を奪われ
悪用されないために➡
So it's necessary to keep the graves
well hidden using things like barriers
結界などで
厳重に墓を隠す必要がある。
so that the bodies will not be stolen
and then used for evil purposes.
それが 隠し墓だ。
That's what
the hidden tombs are.
Then some really amazing Ninja must be
resting in those hidden tombs, huh?
そんじゃ その隠し墓には➡
よっぽど すげぇ忍者が
眠ってるんだな。
Yeah, and
these four in particular.
ああ 特に この４人はな。
They have information just
that worthwhile to steal.
それだけ奪う価値のある
情報を持っている。
No kidding?
へぇ～。
But you know...
there's also one other possibility.
でもね
もう一つの可能性もあるんだ。
それはね… 墓は外から
暴かれたんじゃないってこと。
It could be that the graves weren't
violated from the outside.
んっ？
(ヤマト)つまり➡
In other words...
the bodies came back to life
on the inside and...
中から遺体が よみがえって…。
Yikes!
(ヒッ!?
なんてね！ ハハハ！))
Just kidding.
Naruto believed what
Captain Yamato said...
《ヤマト隊長の言ったこと
信じちゃったんだ…》
I'll do my best!
《がんばるぞ！》
ん…？
This is the rendezvous point.
(ヤマト)ここが 待ち合わせ場所だ。
もうすぐ火ノ寺の人たちが
迎えにくることになっている。
Some people from the Fire Temple
are supposed to come meet us here.
ヒッヒッヒ…！ あ～ オレも疲れたな！
Oh, man. I'm tired, too.
ちょっと座っちゃおっかな…。
え～い うっとうしい！
そっち空いてるでしょ！
Hey, you're irritating me.
You can sit over there!
Okay now.
Don't make so much noise.
(ヤマト)はいはい
あんまり騒がないでね！
I knew it...
He's afraid.
《やっぱり 怖いんだ…》
遅いな… 目印を間違えたかな。
They're late.
I wonder if we've got
the wrong landmark.
I'm going to
have a look over there.
ちょっと そこまで見てくる。
私も行きます！
I'll go, too.
Huh?
Them I'm going, too.
えっ… じゃあ オレも行くよ！
アンタとサイは ここで待ってて。
You and Sai wait here.
We might end up
just missing them.
もしかして 入れ違いに
なるかもしれないじゃない。
…わかったよ。
Fine.
It'll be okay.
(サイ)大丈夫です！
I'll stay with Naruto.
ナルトには ボクがついています。
(２人)はぁ…？
うわっ！
驚かすなっての！
Don't scare me like that!
If a friend is frightened or scared
about something...
《友達がおびえ
怖がっていたら➡
put your hand
gently on their shoulder,
そっと肩に手をやり
ぬくもりを与え➡
provide them with some warmth,
and let them know
they are never alone
決して１人じゃないことを
伝えましょう…》
うん…！
Okay.
Th-This might be...
《こ… これは
思った以上に キツイかも…》
tougher than I thought...
ダ～ッ！ 何すんだよ！
What're you doing?
I-I thought
it would be for the best...
ボクは よかれと思って…。
No way, bruh.
よくねえってばよ！
オレには そんな趣味ねえかんな！
I'm not into stuff like that!
違うって！
そういう意味じゃないって！
No! That's not what I meant!
えっと…
友達に誤解された場合は…。
Uhh, in the case of a
misunderstanding with a friend...
It's totally dangerous for
the two of us to be together!
お前と２人は すげえ危険だ！
Sure enough,
I should be with Sakura-chan!
やっぱり
サクラちゃんと一緒にいる！
ここで こう… ああっ ナルト！
Oh!
Naruto...!
What the hell did I do wrong?
いったい 何を間違えたんだろう？
どうも サイの考えてることは
わけわかんねえってばよ。
I just don't understand what
Sai's thinking about.
Sakura...chan...
サクラちゃん…？
Don't tell me...
it's the grave robber...
《まさか… 墓荒らし》
えっ!?
It's a boar?!
ブタ!?
あぁ やべぇ！
わっ わっ！
I'm sorry!
悪かったってばよ！
Whoa!
Don't come this way!
こ こっち くんなって！
あっ あぁ…。
What's this?
これは…
たしか こんなの前にも…。
I've seen something
like this before...
A barrier?
結界？ ん？
Could this be...
もしかして これが…。
A hidden tomb?!
隠し墓!?
あ…。
なんだってばよ ここ。
What is this place?
棺桶がねえ。 遅かったか。
There's no coffin.
Was I too late?
誰だ！
Who's there?!
《コイツが墓荒らし…》
It's... the grave robber!
《風？》
Wind?
うわっ！
うっ なんだ？
What?!
(ソラ)くらえ！ 獣波掌!!
Eat this!
Beast Wave Palm!
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
あ…！ くっ！
いくぞ！
Here I come!
It's that attack from before...
あれは… さっきの！
獣波掌！
Beast Wave Palm!
フッ…。
《クソ！ やっかいな 風の術だな》
Damn it!
That's an annoying wind Jutsu...
Wind?
I see!
《風… そうか！》
おい！ お前も 風の…。
悔い改めろ！
You also use wind...
It's time for you to repent!
I'll wait three seconds.
３秒待ってやる。
時間切れだ。
バチ当ててやっからよ。
Your time's up.
Now it's divine retribution for you!
くっ… なんだ コイツ!?
バチ当たるのは お前のほうだ！
What's with this guy?!
You're  the one
who'll be getting retribution!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
獣波掌！
Beast Wave Palm!
散れ！
Scatter!
おらぁ！
くらえ！
Eat this!
Beast Wave: Palm Hurricane!
獣波烈風掌！
うおっ！
死ね～っ！
Die!
Enough, Sora!
≪(地陸)やめろ ソラ！
Naruto!
ナルト！
地陸様が
心配してたとおりだったぜ。
It was just as you worried,
Chiriku-sama.
客人を迎えにいく途中で
隠し墓が気になったんで➡
On the way to pick up the guests,
I became concerned about the
hidden tomb and came to have a look.
調べにきたんだ。 そしたら
すでに 結界は破られ➡
And the barrier
had already been broken,
the coffin stolen,
and this guy was there.
柩は盗まれ… 中には コイツが…。
は!? って お前！ 自分の犯行
オレに なすりつけようってのか!?
Are you trying to lay
your crime on me?!
犯人は お前のほうじゃねえかよ！
You're  the one
who's the culprit!
What're you talking about?
何言ってやがる！ 隠し墓に
先に入ってたのは テメエじゃねえか。
You were the one who was
in the hidden tomb first!
The coffin was already gone
when I got there!
オレが入ったときには
すでに 棺桶はなかったんだよ！
Who can corroborate that?!
それを 誰が証明できんだよ！
そっちこそ 誰が証明すんだ!?
Who can corroborate
your story?!
I'll give you the retribution
you deserve, you jerk!
バチ当てんぞ この野郎！
おう 当ててみろ。 当ててみろよ！
Why don't you just try it?!
やってやろうじゃねえか！
I'll just do that!
I won't give in!
負けねえぞ！
コンチクショウめが！ コラァ！
You damned jerk!
Huh?!
What?!
My Leaf brethren!
(地陸)木ノ葉の同胞よ…
私は 火ノ寺の地陸と申す。
My name is Chiriku
of the Fire Temple.
お迎え場所に
手違いがあったため➡
We missed each other due to
a mistake in the rendezvous location.
行き違いとなり
このような誤解を…。
I am terribly sorry
for this misunderstanding.
お詫びいたします。
えっ!?
What?!
This guy's one of the guests?
お客人って コイツ…？
しかも 木ノ葉って！
And he's with the Hidden Leaf?
じゃ コイツってば…。
Then... this guy's...
同じく 火ノ寺の修行僧
ソラと申します。
His name is Sora.
He is a trainee monk
of the same Fire Temple.
ソラ君だね。
Sora, huh?
My name's Yamato and
I am the captain of this team.
ボクは この班の班長の ヤマト。
This is Naruto and...
そして ナルトと…。
I'm Sakura.
サクラです。
サイと言います。
My name's... Sai.
…オレ 言いましたよね？
I told you we don't need any help
from the likes of the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉の助けなんて
いらねえって。
ソラ。
Sora!
(忍僧)地陸様！ 証拠となるものは
跡形もなく➡
Chiriku-sama!
There's not a shred of evidence
キタネ様の棺桶ごと
持ち去られております…。
and Lord Kitane's coffin and
all have been taken.
結界を破った手際といい
かなり高度な忍かと思われます。
The barrier was
broken with great skill...
and we believe it was a Shinobi
of considerable power.
ふぅ…。
敵が そうとうの忍であるなら➡
If the enemy is
a Shinobi of great ability,
木ノ葉の方々を
呼んだかいはある。
then it was worthwhile summoning
the people from the Hidden Leaf.
Head on back and arrange
to have skilled individuals
お前は 先に戻って
他の３つの隠し墓に➡
guard the other
three hidden tombs!
手練れの手配を。
更に 緊急の場合に備え➡
And tighten security
around the Fire Temple
火ノ寺の警護を 強化せよ。
(２人)はっ！
in preparation
for a potential emergency.
Yes, sir!
とりあえず 貴殿らは火ノ寺へ。
You guys head to
the Fire Temple for now.
わかりました。
Understood.
Hey, any chance your Chakra has
the wind property?
なぁ お前のチャクラって
ひょっとして 風の性質？
人が しゃべってんのに
無視すんな！
Don't ignore someone when
they're talking to you!
I'm talking about
your Jutsu from before!
さっきの術のことだってばよ！
…確か こっちの手だった。
さわるんじゃねえ！
It was this hand, wasn't it?
Don't touch me!
Jerk...
コイツ…。
はぁ…。
あ～ まだ着かねえの？
Are we there yet?
うん？
あのときの夢と… 同じ…。
It's the same as my dream...
from back then.
I look up at the rainbow I saw as a child.
kodomo no koro mita niji wo
But the prism colors are gone,
ima miageru to nanairo de wa naku
Shrouded in mist instead.
yagate kiri ga kakari
I search for you as you change,
jikan wa sugi kawatte yuku
With the passage of time but you're nowhere to be found.
kimi wo sagashite mo doko ni mo inai
I close my eyes and open my heart.
me wo toji kokoro hiraite
And stare hard again just to see if nothing really changes.
mata nagemete mite mo nani mo kawaranai no ka
I need to know.
tashikamete mitai
I make a wish that the mist will clear.
sunao ni narereba kono kiri ga hareru to
If I'm true to myself and shout it out.
kokoro ni negai sou sakenderu
Maybe by losing something.
nanika wo nakushite shimatta koto de sou
There must be something I gain as well.
te ni shita mono mo kitto arun darou
((ナルト…。
(サクラちゃん…))
But we're still confused about adulthood.
dakedo mada bokura wa otona ni tomadoi
And searching for the means to live on.
ikito yuku sube sagashiteru
(サクラ)ナルト！
いつまで寝てんのよ！
任務に遅れるわよ！
う～ん…
あ サクラちゃん。 ん～！
Next Episode
Hey, Naruto.
寝ぼけるな！
イテテテ…。
What's been annoying
you since earlier?
…にしても
よく こんな汚い部屋で平気ね。
Looking at that jerk
Sora's movements,
it's like he's
mocking training,
ラーメンは 食べっぱなし。
just doing it any old way,
or something...
賞味期限切れの牛乳は
そのまんま。
Huh? Why?
He's training hard, isn't he?
いいかげん 掃除したら？
That's not what I mean.
Compared to his movements when
he came at me before...
いや… エヘヘ…。
うわぁ～!!
Oh, I can't take it.
I'm going to complain.
うわぁ！
Hey, Naruto...
サクラ… ちゃん。
For crying out loud! Hold it.
イタタ… う～… 何なのよ これ。
Loneliness
Next time: "Loneliness"
Naruto...
この… バカナルト!!
Sakura-chan...
だは！
Naruto!
Are you going to sleep forever?!
We'll be late for our mission!
Oh, Sakura-chan...
Wake up sleepyhead!
Ow-ow-ow...
At any rate...
...how can you even live
in such a filthy room...?
Half-eaten ramen.
Expired milk left out.
Why don't you clean up
this place already?!
Sakura-chan...
Ow-ow-ow...
- For crying out loud! What is...this...?
- Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa...
You idiot, Naruto!